<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:cav="http://cavatinafont.com/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1-extended">
    <?dbhtml filename="general_concept.html" ?>

    <info>
        <title>General concept</title>
    </info>

    <para>Cavatina is a language for creating musical notation and a font system that renders it. It focuses on
        ease of input and portability and is primarly suited for music teaching and quick drafting of ideas. Portability
        is achieved in a very unique manner. Cavatina sheet music <emphasis role="italic">is</emphasis> text and as such it will support all common text
        manipulation commands. As you write, the input is interpreted straight away
        by the text engine, so that firstly it won't feel like coding and, more importantly, there is no need to
        “compile” it. This makes Cavatina really portable. It is ideal for traveling and teaching music. Also, it can be
        easily embedded as a webfont in any website.
    </para>

    <para>The font implements a rendering concept which could be called <emphasis role="italic">image-as-text</emphasis>, using implicit compilation of a text
        engine via contextual character substitutions. This has the advantage of supporting all common text manipulation functions of any
        rich text editor, such as copy, paste, cut, and undo. As a plain font, Cavatina can be embedded into a web page
        or web app with minimal effort.
    </para>

    <cav:music-notation>+---~24 ] g|| g.. g.., D~"", ] f|| f.. f.., S~L, S~"",</cav:music-notation>

    <note>
        <title>Browser support</title>
        <para>Cavatina renders on the latest versions of Chrome, Firefox and Opera. Tested on Windows 10 and MacOS High Sierra.</para>
    </note>
    

    <section>
        <?dbhtml filename="language_overview.html" ?>

        <title>Language overview</title>
        <para>You type in your music <emphasis role="italic">sequentially</emphasis>, i.e. the same
            way as in written language. Chords are words, bar-lines are punctuation marks,
            accidentals are diacritics and staff lines are the space character. Here is the base of
            Cavatina’s syntax:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Hitting space extends the staff for starting a new note/chord.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Notes within a chord are typed in <emphasis role="italic">from low to high</emphasis>.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Note modifiers are written directly <emphasis role="italic">after</emphasis> the corresponding
                    note.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
        <?dbhtml filename="character_mapping.html" ?>

        <title>Character mapping</title>
        <para>Notes and all other musical symbols are accessed directly with your computer keyboard. The input depends
            on what keyboard layout you use.
            The complete keyboard mapping for each layout can be found on the <link
                    xlink:href="http://cavatinafont.com/en/keyboard">keyboard page</link>. If you are new to
            Cavatina, it is a better idea to read through the short documentation first.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
